- [Instructor] Now the fun begins.
We'll start by creating our initial server code
and making sure it is running properly.
We'll simply work on the basis of our server,
which will add more and more as we build our backend APIs.
So the first thing we're going to do
is go inside the package.json file, right here.
And you can close the babelrc file.
And what we're going to do is add a little script.
You can move the test script, I usually do.
So I'm just going to remove this one.
And basically do a start script,
which I will basically write down this specific script
when we do npm start.
So it's going to be nodemon.
And we're going to be loading the index.js file.
And then we're going to execute through babel-node
and transpile the code using JavaScript.
So basically we're passing a nodemon script.
A nodemon, by the way, is basically
a server that restarts automatically
every time you do changes.
And we're passing the index.js file
that we're going to create momentarily.
And we're executing and transpiling the code
with babel-node.
So, you can save that.
And now what we're going to do is create,
inside the backend folder again,
the index.js file.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And inside of that file,
we're going to first import express.
From express.
Then we're going to create our server app
by passing the express server.
And then we're going to create the port
that our server is going to be running on.
So the variable that's going to pass the actual port number
so we can leverage it across several functions.
In this case, we're just going to choose 4000.
And then what we're going to do is use the express app.
And whenever we're calling this endpoint,
we're going to basically send that request
and send a response to this function.
And we're going to have a response and send it.
"Our application is running."
And we should use template strings and not regular strings.
So I'm going to do this
to pass the port inside of this string here.
"On port."
And how you use template strings,
if you're not familiar with it,
it's dollar sign and pass inside here
the variable that we set here.
So it's going to basically run this message and send it,
"Our application is running on port,"
whatever the port is.
So we're good.
Then we're going to be listening
to whenever the port is being request,
we're going to also, in the console log, run this command.
And then use template stringing again.
"Your soccer server is running on port,"
and then pass port.
Okay.
So now, this is all good.
We can actually save this.
And go inside of our terminal again,
I'm going to use the shortcut here to get into it.
If you're not familiar with the shortcuts,
all you have to do is click on Terminal, New Terminal,
and you're going to see the shortcut for your own system.
And I'm going to do an npm start.
And then it says, "Your soccer server
is running on port 4000."
If you open up a new window
and you do localhost:4000,
you're going to see that the message and the response is,
"Our application is running on port 4000."
Okay. So we got our server running,
ready to add more stuff to it.
So let's move on.